In this lesson we're going to be exploring arrow functions, which is a modern and concise
way to write your functions in JavaScript as well as TypeScript.
So we're going to learn how to type their parameters and return values and how they differ
from regular functions and when to use them in your code.
So first of all, what exactly is an arrow function?
So an arrow function is basically a shorthand syntax for writing our functions.
And in particular they're useful for doing things like callbacks or just inline logic
and if you're into a functional programming.
So let's do a quick example and we're just going to have a normal greet function here
where we supply a name and notice we say const rather than a function.
So we greet, it takes our parameter of name, it returns a string.
And this is where our arrow function definition comes in between equals and then a greater
than sign.
And then we define the actual function like this and just do return whatever the messages
like hello and then the person's name, etc.
Now you can also do this in line so rather than having a curly brace like this we could
simply just do return then that hello and then the person's name.
Now even shorter hand we're doing that if it's very straightforward is we can get rid
of the curly brace completely, it rid of the return and simply do something like this
and just do hello and then dollar then name.
And it can happen all in one as you can see is nice and concise.
Now this is also true for doing type inference as well.
So if we have for example, so we could do constant and double this ethics number and then
we can simply do x times 2 and of course the TypeScript's then going to immediately know
that this is a number that we're trying to return.
Let's look at a couple more examples and particularly using the aliases.
So let's say we're trying to do a formatter, perhaps capitalizing the letter of a word.
We could define a formatter shape like this so formatter this has taken a value which is
of type string and this then returns a string.
Then we could define our function, let's say capitalize capitalize.
This is a type of alias of formatter where we take a say perhaps a supply that's some
text and then just take our text and we'll just do something like 0 and then to uppercase
and then the rest of the text, blah, blah, blah.
But you can see I'm not going to finish the function, you can see how this is going to work.
So you can see that here it's a kind of nice way of being able to carry on just like we did
in the previous lesson for to finding kind of short functions in this kind of format by using
the arrow function.